Humanity was suddenly reminded that day...
...of the terror of being at their mercy...
...of the humiliation
of being trapped inside a cage...
All soldiers, prepare for battle!
We have one target!
We will slay it and claim this spot
as humanity's first stronghold
beyond the walls!
Target approaching!
Split into five groups just as we practiced!
We'll act as the bait!
All assault squads,
switch to omni-directional gear!
Strike from all directions at once!
Taste the power...
...of humanity!
Unknown are the names
of the flowers that have been trampled
Birds have fallen to the earth
and long for the wind
Prayers won't solve anything
Only the will to fight
can change the here and now!
O pigs who laugh at the resolve
to walk over corpses to move forward
Livestock complacency? False prosperity?
Give us the freedom of dying,
starving wolves!
The humiliation of being caged
is what triggers us to fight back
We hunters slaughter prey
beyond the castle walls,
consumed with surging bloodlust,
as our crimson bows and arrows
pierce scarlet holes into the twilight
"To You, in 2000 Years"
"The Fall of Shiganshina, Part 1"
Huh? Mikasa...
We should be getting back.
What are we doing here...?
You were that deep asleep
that you're still only half-awake?
No...
It just feels like I had this
really long dream or something...
What was it about?
I can't remember...
Eren, why are you crying?
Huh?
"Year 845 Shiganshina District"
Listen!
It was by God's great wisdom
that the walls were built!
The walls are His divine work!
No one must be allowed to defile the walls!
Don't you dare tell anyone I was crying.
I won't.
Still, crying for no real reason...
You should have your dad give you a checkup.
Don't be stupid! I can't tell him!
What are you cryin' about, Eren?
Mr. Hannes...
Did Mikasa get on your case about somethin'?
Huh?! What makes you think I was crying?!
Whoa, you reek of alcohol!
It's like, come on, y'know?
Oh.
You're drinking again...
You guys wanna join in?
Actually, uhh... Don't you have work?
Yup! We're guardin' the gate today!
We're stuck here all day,
so we end up getting hungry and thirsty.
If some booze happens to get into our drinks,
so what? It's no big deal.
What if something happens?!
Can you fight like that?!
--Whadya mean, "If something happens"?
--You know what I mean!
I'm talking about if
they break the walls and get into the city!
Oww...
Geez, Eren. Don't go yellin' like that.
You've got spunk, doctor's son!
If they do bust down the walls,
we'll take care of business, don't you worry.
But that ain't happened once
in the last one hundred years.
Still, my dad says there's nothing
more dangerous than being complacent like that!
Dr. Jaeger, huh?
Yeah, he's got a point.
He once saved this town from an epidemic.
I can't argue with him.
Still, they're another story altogether.
When you're a soldier, you get to see
those things roaming around outside
while you're on
wall reinforcement duty and stuff.
These walls are fifty meters tall, though.
I can't see 'em getting through.
Then... you're not actually
prepared to fight them at all?!
Nope!
Wh-What?!
Then drop the "Garrison Regiment" name
for "Wall Construction Squad" instead!
Not a bad idea!
But you gotta understand, Eren.
If a soldier's doing his job,
things have seriously gone to hell.
It's better when everyone's
calling us useless freeloaders;
it means peaceful times for us all.
Sure, we can stay
inside the walls our entire lives
and do nothing but eat and sleep!
But... that basically...
That basically makes us cattle!
Man, you're one plucky kid, all right!
For someone who's totally helpless!
Right, Hannes?!
Huh? Y-Yeah.
Hey! Eren!
What a weirdo!
Wait... Don't tell me
he wants to join the Scout Regiment?
Eren, I'd forget about
the Scout Regiment if I were you.
What?! You think the Scout Regiment
is a joke too?!
It's not about what I think.
The Scout Regiment is back!
They're gonna open the front gate!
Let's go see the heroes return, Mikasa!
Oh...!
Damn! I can't see!
They're the only ones who made it back?
Everyone else must've gotten eaten.
This is what they get
for going outside the walls.
Moses! Moses!
Excuse me...
I don't see my son Moses anywhere...
Do you know where he is?
This is Moses' mother.
Go get it.
It's all we could retrieve.
But... my son...
He was helpful, yes?
Even if he didn't achieve direct greatness...
...surely my son's death
helped humanity fight back, yes?!
Of course...!
No...
On this latest scouting mission, we...
Just like all the other missions...
...we achieved nothing at all!
My incompetence has done nothing
but needlessly send soldiers to their deaths!
We haven't found out anything about them!
Talk about gruesome.
You can say that again.
Our taxes are basically going
to feeding and fattening those things up now.
What the hell, you little punk?!
H-Hey! What are you doing, Mikasa?!
Hey! Get back here, you!
Mikasa! Enough already!
What's the big idea?!
Now the firewood's all over the place!
Eren.
Have you changed your mind
about joining the Scout Regiment?
Help pick this up.
It's not that bad of a mess.
We're home.
Welcome back.
Wow, Eren! You actually worked hard!
Yeah...
What do you want?
Your ear's red. That shows that you're lying.
You had Mikasa help you, didn't you?
Oh? You're leaving, Dad?
Is it for work?
Yes, some checkups in the interior.
It'll take a couple of days.
Eren says he wants to join the Scout Regiment.
M-Mikasa! I told you not to say anything!
Eren!
What are you thinking?!
Do you have any idea how many people
have died outside the walls?!
--Y-Yeah, I know!
--Then...!
Eren.
Why do you want to go out there?
I want to know what the outside world is like!
I don't want to live my entire life
in ignorance inside the walls!
Plus...
If no one else is willing to take their place,
then the lives of all who've died
will be for nothing!
I see.
My boat's about to leave. I better get going.
Hold on, dear! Talk some sense into Eren!
Carla.
Words can't hold back human curiosity.
Eren.
When I get back, I'll show you the basement
that I've kept secret all this time.
R-Really?!
Take care!
Just forget it.
Joining the Scout Regiment is a stupid idea!
Huh?! Stupid?!
People who don't mind living like livestock
are the stupid ones, if you ask me!
Eren!
Mikasa.
He gets himself into trouble so easily.
If anything ever happens,
you need to be there for each other!
Mm.
What's the matter, heretic?!
If you don't like it, let's see you hit back!
Y-Yeah, right!
That would be stooping to your level!
Say what?!
You know I'm right!
That's why you have to resort to violence!
Because you can't argue back!
Which means you
concede defeat to me, does it not?!
Shut up, smart-ass!
Stop that!
It's Eren!
--That idiot's back for more?!
--Does he want his ass kicked?!
We'll tear you a new one!
M-Mikasa's with him!
S-Screw this! Let's get outta here!
One look at me and they ran off!
No, it was Mikasa they saw...
Oww!
Hey! You okay, Armin?!
I can get up on my own...
Oh.
I said humanity needs to venture
into the outside world at some point...
...and then they beat me up
and called me a heretic.
Damn...
Why does everyone look down on people
just for wanting to go outside?!
Well, because we've had
a hundred years of peace
by staying inside the walls.
They're worried that going outside carelessly
will invite them inside the walls.
The royal government's policies have made
having any interest
in the outside world a taboo.
It's our lives! We can risk 'em if we want!
Absolutely not.
Forget about it.
Which reminds me,
I can't believe you told my parents!
Huh?
I never agreed to help.
So, what did they say?
They're... less than pleased.
It figures.
Indeed, I think people are crazy
if they think we'll be
safe inside these walls forever.
Mommy!
Just because the walls
haven't fallen for a hundred years
doesn't guarantee that they won't fall today....
And yet...
Wh-What was that?!
An explosion?!
--That way!
--Did something fall?!
I'm not really sure...
Hey, Armin!
What is it?! What do you see?!
It can't be...!
Th-That wall... is fifty meters high!
It's one of them...
A Titan!
I-It... opened a hole in the wall...
They're inside!
The Titans have gotten inside!
We need to run too!
Eren!
My house is in that direction!
Mom...!
Mikasa!
It's all over...
Countless Titans... are going to overrun the city!
It couldn't have hit our home!
Just around this corner...
our house is standing there, like always!
Mom!
--Eren!
--Mikasa! Grab that end!
We gotta move this pillar!
Hurry, Mikasa!
I know!
The Titans have gotten inside, haven't they?
Eren! Take Mikasa and run away!
Hurry!
I want to!
So hurry and get out of there!
The debris has crushed my legs...
Even if I could get out,
I wouldn't be able to run.
You understand what that means.
I'll carry you, then!
Why don't you ever listen to your mother?!
You can at least do this one last thing!
Mikasa!
No...
No...!
If you don't go, all three of us will...
Hannes!
Take the children and get out of here!
Don't go underestimatin' me, Carla.
I'm gonna slaughter these Titans
and save all three of ya!
Wait! Don't fight them!
Yeah, I could save those two for sure.
But now...
I'm finally going to repay the favor I owe!
Hey! Mr. Hannes!
What are you doing?!
--Thank you...
--Hey!
Mom's still...!
Eren! Mikasa!
You have to survive!
Don't go...
Stop!
Humanity was suddenly reminded that day...
...of the terror of being at their mercy...
...of the humiliation
of being trapped inside a cage...
Your dreams are where your heart is
They're more fragile than life itself
Over and over you cast them aside,
only to find more
Now, rest in peace
Pounding impulses defile the things we wish for
and the more we forget
the more we remember again
In this beautiful, cruel world
all I can do is ask why we're still alive
Oh, with our strength--and our weakness--
what are we going to protect if there's no sense
to anything anymore?
Shiganshina falls.
Prayers, screams, and death
are all that humanity is allowed.
Amid this, Eren alone
swears revenge in his small heart.